<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CENTEXGIS</title>
    <description>A GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SYSTEMS USER GROUP SERVING CENTRAL TEXAS</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 14:44:50 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 14:44:50 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: TCEQ Job Posting - Program Supervisor</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;texas-commission-on-environmental-quality-job-posting&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Texas Commission on Environmental Quality Job Posting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;email-applications-to-jobstceqtexasgov&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email applications to: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jobs@tceq.texas.gov&quot;&gt;jobs@tceq.texas.gov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TCEQ: &lt;a href=&quot;www.tceq.texas.gov&quot;&gt;www.tceq.texas.gov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
State Title: &lt;strong&gt;Program Supervisor VII&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Job Posting: 18145&lt;br /&gt;
Monthly Salary: &lt;strong&gt;$5258.66 - $5924.35&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Salary Group: &lt;strong&gt;B25&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Posting Date: 01/26/2018&lt;br /&gt;
Close Date: 02/09/2018&lt;br /&gt;
Section/Division: Enterprise Support Section/Information Resources Division&lt;br /&gt;
Work Location: 12100 Park 35 Circle, Austin, TX 78753&lt;br /&gt;
Openings: One&lt;br /&gt;
Position #(s): 0919&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Job Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Supervises and oversees technical team in the delivery of information technology
services and products utilized by the Texas Commission on Environmental Quality.
Leads and directs the Enterprise Reporting and Geographic Information Systems
Team, prioritizes and delegates tasks, and participates in establishing daily and long range
duties and objectives. Completes personnel management functions, which
includes interviews, hiring, developing staff, and establishing metrics for performance
management, etc. Communicates with customers, management, consultants, and coworkers
to ascertain information needs; and disseminates appropriate information to
meet the data requirements of customers. Analyzes and evaluates business practices
and service requirements regarding the use of technology, data, and communications
as it relates to business area needs. Recommends changes where appropriate to
more effectively meet enterprise and customer needs. Ensures progress toward
operational and strategic goals, which involves reporting to management regarding
the nature and extent of customer demand for information, and the level of customer
satisfaction with the information provided. Coordinates and/or provides direction for
the management of multiple IT projects or initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimum Qualifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Experience in the administration of a program relevant to assignment.
OR Graduation from an accredited four-year college or university with major course
work in a field relevant to assignment (COPY OF OFFICIAL TRANSCRIPT REQUIRED
WITH APPLICATION).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preferred Qualifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Experience supervising or managing IT teams.
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science or Management Information Systems.
Experience working with Crystal Reports and Web Intelligence reporting tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To Apply&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Email a State of Texas application to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jobs@tceq.texas.gov&quot;&gt;jobs@tceq.texas.gov&lt;/a&gt;; or mail to TCEQ Human Resources &amp;amp; Staff Services, P.O. Box 13087, MC-116 Austin, TX 78711-3087; or
submit in person, at 12100 Park 35 Circle, Bldg. A, Austin, Texas 78753 by the close
date. An electronically signed copy is acceptable.&lt;br /&gt;
In compliance with ADA, if you need any special accommodations during the
employment process, please contact HRSS for assistance at (512) 239-0102.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 15:39:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/jobs/tceq-job-program-supervisor</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/jobs/tceq-job-program-supervisor</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>Jobs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: CenTexGIS Meeting September 27, 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: left;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/centex.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;please-mark-your-calendars-and-make-plans-to-join-us-for-the-upcoming-centexgis-user-group-meeting&quot;&gt;Please mark your calendars and make plans to join us for the upcoming CenTexGIS user group meeting!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meeting is scheduled for &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, September 27th 4:00 - 6:00 PM&lt;/strong&gt; at the Flying Saucer (Triangle location - &lt;em&gt;The Hall&lt;/em&gt; is reserved).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you will come out to this important event and meet with local GIS colleagues and friends to learn, network and help strengthen GIS community bonds through knowledge sharing and support. &lt;strong&gt;Devon Humphrey&lt;/strong&gt;, Founder of &lt;strong&gt;Flightline Geographics&lt;/strong&gt;, will join us and talk with the group about emerging UAS technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please try to arrive a few minutes early to find parking, sign in, and grab a tasty snack or beverage.  Following the meeting we have the option to hang out in the restaurant or patio areas to network and socialize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, one lucky winner will go home with a great DOOR PRIZE.  We hope to see you in a couple weeks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 13:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/gis/events/centexgis-september-meeting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/gis/events/centexgis-september-meeting</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>GIS</category>
        
        <category>Events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Alamo Area GIS Conference</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/aagis.png&quot; alt=&quot;AAGIS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Inaugural Professional GIS Conference hosted by the Alamo Area GIS User Group will be September 6th &amp;amp; 7th at the Hilton San Antonio Hill Country
Hotel &amp;amp; Spa in San Antonio, TX. This is the last week to register!
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introducing the AAGIS Professional GIS Conference! Join us this September for this inaugural event as we come together with our GIS colleagues to develop
professionally and network with like-minded individuals. More details are posted at &lt;a href=&quot;http://aagis.org&quot;&gt;www.aagis.org&lt;/a&gt; so make sure to keep checking for
updates. Registration is now open and can be accessed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aagis.org/conference/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Please share with other GIS professionals. This event is
open to all and is not limited to only AAGIS members. We look forward to seeing you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/gis/events/alamo-area-gis-conference</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/gis/events/alamo-area-gis-conference</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>GIS</category>
        
        <category>Events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: TNRIS GIS Forum 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/bigtex_empty.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TNRIS GIS Forum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For 30 years, the Texas GIS Forum has been the can’t-miss event for the statewide GIS community. Come to Austin this fall to hear about the latest advancements in GIS and take the opportunity to touch base with long-time colleagues – as well as make new connections.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lost-as-a-child-online-maps-pointed-to-hometown---forum-keynote-saroo-brierley&quot;&gt;Lost as a Child, Online Maps Pointed To Hometown - Forum Keynote, Saroo Brierley&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/saroo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Saroo Key Note Speaker&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celebrating the 30th Annual Texas GIS Forum, Saroo Brierley, our keynote speaker, has a story that profoundly intersects his personal history with the power of modern geography and online mapping tools. Saroo will share his extraordinary story with us on Thursday, October 26, at Austin’s landmark destination, The Oasis Restaurant at Lake Travis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;register-for-the-event-below-and-take-advantage-of-lower-prices-before-september-22nd&quot;&gt;Register for the event below and take advantage of lower prices before September 22nd!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;register-here&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.regonline.com/registration/checkin.aspx?MethodId=0&amp;amp;EventSessionId=5cdfe0598c364b169bf9ecbd9886bc35&amp;amp;EventId=2011451&quot;&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;view-more-information-about-the-tnris-gis-forum-here&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tnris.org/texas-gis-forum/2017/&quot;&gt;View more information about the TNRIS GIS Forum here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 10:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/gis/events/tnris-gis-forum-2017</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/gis/events/tnris-gis-forum-2017</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>GIS</category>
        
        <category>Events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: WDS &amp; Trimble User Group Meeting &amp; Tech Exhibit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/wds.png&quot; alt=&quot;WDS&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/trimble.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Trimble&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WDS &amp;amp; Trimble invite you to attend the 2017 User Group Meeting and Technology Exhibit featuring guest speakers and industry experts presenting technical seminars on a variety of Geospatial topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take advantage of this opportunity to increase your knowledge of industry related topics that will enhance your productivity and broaden your understanding of important topics you face every day as a Geospatial Professional.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;seminar-tracks-include&quot;&gt;SEMINAR TRACKS INCLUDE:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;mapping--gis&quot;&gt;MAPPING / GIS&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coordinate Systems and Datums&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collector for ArcGIS Integration with High Accuracy Trimble MGIS Receivers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increase your Field Efficiency with P.L.A.N.I.T.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;LTI workflows/or integration with Trimble products&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;survey&quot;&gt;SURVEY&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trimble Connect - Field to Office Realtime Data Transfer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grid to Ground Coordinates: A Discussion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SX10 Scanning Robot - Workflow &amp;amp; Features&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SX10 and VISION Deliverables in TBC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;plus&quot;&gt;PLUS:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous vendors will be on-hand displaying and demonstrating a variety of Geospatial Technologies used in field data capture and data processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;click-the-link-below-to-register-today&quot;&gt;Click the link below to Register Today!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lunch is included with your registration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Early Registration Discounts are Available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;get-more-information-here&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://events.r20.constantcontact.com/register/event?llr=xw5fseoab&amp;amp;oeidk=a07eefa35or460d9264&quot;&gt;Get more information here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;register-for-the-event-here&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.r20.constantcontact.com/register/eventReg?oeidk=a07eefa35or460d9264&amp;amp;oseq=&amp;amp;c=&amp;amp;ch=&quot;&gt;Register for the event here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact them today if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Western Data Systems, Inc. (WDS)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:wds@wds-us.com&quot;&gt;wds@wds-us.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
281-987-1815&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 10:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/gis/events/wds-trimble-user-group-meeting-tech-exhibit</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/gis/events/wds-trimble-user-group-meeting-tech-exhibit</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>GIS</category>
        
        <category>Events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: GIS Technician - Enco</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/enco.png&quot; alt=&quot;Enco Consulting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;gis-technician&quot;&gt;GIS Technician&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;enco-consulting---austin-tx&quot;&gt;Enco Consulting - Austin, TX&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enco Consulting is looking for a GIS Technician, must have GIS Certification or equivalent courses and work experience. Need to know the ArcGIS Desktop platform and be comfortable editing and annotation data. Knowledge of GPS and willingness to endure outdoor conditions to accomplish field checks desired. Preferred candidate understands how to read plat maps, as-builts and constructions plans. QGIS and AutoCAD are a plus. The position is in our Lakeway office. Send questions or resumes to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jacq@enco.net&quot;&gt;jacq@enco.net&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 10:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/jobs/gis/enco-gis-technician</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/jobs/gis/enco-gis-technician</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>Jobs</category>
        
        <category>GIS</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: GIS Software Developer - Atkins</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/atkins.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Atkins&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;gis-software-developer&quot;&gt;GIS Software Developer&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;atkins---anywhere-in-north-america&quot;&gt;Atkins - Anywhere in North America&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atkins seeks an energetic and highly motivated self-starter to join our Atkins North America Technology Group as a GIS Software Developer. This position can sit in any Atkins North American hub office in the United States.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
Atkins has been providing infrastructure planning, engineering, construction, environmental consulting, urban planning, architecture, and program management services to public and private clients across the United States for more than 50 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Globally, Atkins is the largest UK-based engineering and design consultancy and one of the world’s largest design firms with nearly 18,000 employees worldwide. We have the depth and breadth of expertise to respond to the most technically challenging and time-critical infrastructure projects and the urgent transition to a low-carbon economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;major-functionrole&quot;&gt;Major Function/Role&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applies professional proficiency in the development of custom software applications and the coordination of related activities in support of projects that meet clients’ software development needs. At this level, works under supervision on assignments that have clear and specified objectives. Candidate will be focused on GIS development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;job-duties&quot;&gt;Job Duties&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Participates in client needs analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Develops customized applications by writing well-documented code in the applicable environment to meet documented software requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May participate in collection, conversion, and assembly of data in a variety of formats.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May participate in documentation and diagramming of business and technical requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;May participate in database/application design.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Performs maintenance tasks on existing projects following the project’s established architecture/design.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Prepares data documentation for projects, following prescribed Best Practices.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maintains continued knowledge of technology developments in the field and use of applicable programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Monitors quality control within area of responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Manages commitments to complete tasks within given schedule and budget.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Performs such other duties as the Supervisor may from time to time deem necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;education-and-experience&quot;&gt;Education and Experience&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B.S. or B.A in Computer Science, Geography with a focus on GIS, IT-related discipline, or four years’ relevant computer programming experience after degrees in Engineering, or other related disciplines. This level may be achieved by practitioners with 2 years of experience since related Bachelor’s degree; minimal experience required with related Master’s degree if academic program provided opportunity to develop software development experience directly applicable to job. Non-degreed practitioners must demonstrate at least six years of direct experience in lieu of degree. Typical incumbent has 4-6 years’ experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;special-skills&quot;&gt;Special Skills&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must demonstrate programming skills and experience with current object-oriented programming techniques, and work experience in the following: C#, Java, .NET, C++, HTML, JavaScript and/or similar, with ability and willingness to learn others as needed. Database experience required in at least one of the following: Microsoft SQL, Oracle, or similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should have good interpersonal, technical writing and communications skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GIS development experience required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience programming using Esri JavaScript API, Python and experience with Esri Enterprise Geodatabases required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge of Portal for ArcGIS a plus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience with Xamarin, Android or iOS a plus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;professional-registrations&quot;&gt;Professional Registrations&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GISP certification a plus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;additional-requirements&quot;&gt;Additional requirements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Competencies expected of all Professionals and Managers are as follows: Client Service, Commitment, Communication, Innovation &amp;amp; Continuous Improvement, Professionalism, Quality, and Teamwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Job requires ability to access and understand technology materials and ability to operate computer keyboard. Ability to communicate effectively both orally and in writing. Incumbent must be able and willing to deal with interruptions in current work in progress to handle priority jobs. Ability to plan and prioritize tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atkins offers its employees a robust rewards package which includes: a competitive salary; a broad benefits package including medical/RX, dental, vision, life, disability, legal, hospitalization and other valuable voluntary options; generous time-off programs; flexible work schedules; 401(k) with employer match; professional and career development opportunities through our corporate university, as well as a highly-regarded tuition reimbursement program; and an unmatched culture focused on client-service, quality, and tireless pursuit of excellence in all we do. Atkins is an equal opportunity, drug-free employer committed to diversity in the workplace. EOE/Minorities/Females/Vet/Disability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://careers.atkinsglobal.com/job/gis-software-developer-jobid-na-001518&quot;&gt;https://careers.atkinsglobal.com/job/gis-software-developer-jobid-na-001518&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 10:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/jobs/gis/atkins-gis-software-developer</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/jobs/gis/atkins-gis-software-developer</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>Jobs</category>
        
        <category>GIS</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: ATX GIS Day is Back!!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/gis_day.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ATX GIS Day&quot; title=&quot;ATX GIS Day&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;atx-gis-day-is-back-this-year-and-the-planning-committee-has-been-hard-at-work-preparing-for-this-years-event&quot;&gt;ATX GIS Day is back this year and the planning committee has been hard at work preparing for this year’s event!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Help us make this year spectacular by providing activity and venue ideas below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeapUlSaaPK3WDKAoJ6wQfrkh98OC-cnquRi8gw9UUQVfPzpw/viewform&quot;&gt;ATX GIS Day Activity Survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We are looking for new and engaging ideas for ATX GIS Day 2017. You can submit as few or as many ideas as you’d like. We’ve provided a few guided questions to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://austin.maps.arcgis.com/apps/CrowdsourceReporter/index.html?appid=93e986d5a85a4dfba46738be94f6f898&quot;&gt;ATX GIS Day Venue Crowdsourcing Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We are looking for venue ideas to host ATX GIS Day 2017. Add as many venue ideas as you’d like. Details about the venue are great but not necessary. The main criteria to consider is a central location to the Austin area and free parking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both surveys will close next Wednesday 8/16/17.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!
The ATX GIS Day Planning Team&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 15:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/gis/events/atx-gis-day</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/gis/events/atx-gis-day</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>GIS</category>
        
        <category>Events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: The New Plot to Hijack GIS and Mapping</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A bill recently introduced in the U.S. Senate could effectively exclude everyone but licensed architects, engineers, and surveyors from federal government contracts for GIS and mapping services of all kinds — not just those services traditionally provided by surveyors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Geospatial Data Act (GDA) of 2017 (S.1253) would set up a system of exclusionary procurement that would prevent most companies and organizations in the dynamic and rapidly growing GIS and mapping sector from receiving federal contracts for a very wide range of activities, including GPS field data collection, GIS, internet mapping, geospatial analysis, location based services, remote sensing, academic research involving maps, and digital or manual map making or cartography of almost any type.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only would this bill limit competition, innovation and free-market approaches for a crucial high-growth information technology (IT) sector of the U.S. economy, it also would cripple the current vibrant GIS industry and damage U.S. geographic information science, research capacity, and competitiveness. The proposed bill would also shackle government agencies, all of which depend upon the productivity, talent, scientific and technical skills, and the creativity and innovation that characterize the vast majority of the existing GIS and mapping workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read this complete article &lt;a href=&quot;https://aag.informz.net/informzdataservice/onlineversion/ind/bWFpbGluZ2luc3RhbmNlaWQ9NjcwMzEyMyZzdWJzY3JpYmVyaWQ9MTA5OTMzNzQ0NQ==&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, stay updated on the  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.govtrack.us/congress/bills/115/s1253&quot;&gt;bill’s progress&lt;/a&gt;, or view the entirety of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/senate-bill/1253/text&quot;&gt;Geospatial Data Act of 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 11:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/gis/the-new-plot-to-hijack-gis-and-mapping</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/gis/the-new-plot-to-hijack-gis-and-mapping</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>GIS</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: June 2017 CENTEX GIS Meeting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/centex.png&quot; alt=&quot;centex gis&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;please-mark-your-calendars-and-make-plans-to-join-us-for-the-upcoming-centexgis-user-group-meeting&quot;&gt;Please mark your calendars and make plans to join us for the upcoming CenTexGIS user group meeting!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;date-june-27-2017&quot;&gt;Date: June 27, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;time-330---530pm&quot;&gt;Time: 3:30 - 5:30pm&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;location-austin-history-center---810-guadalupe-st-austin-tx-78701&quot;&gt;Location: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Austin+History+Center,+Austin+Public+Library/@30.2717133,-97.7469814,18z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x8644b50bc234d3c3:0x2ac89189e352c67e!8m2!3d30.2717133!4d-97.7458871&quot;&gt;Austin History Center - 810 Guadalupe St., Austin, TX, 78701&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you will come out to this important event and meet with local GIS colleagues and friends to learn, network and help strengthen GIS community bonds through knowledge sharing and support. The proposed agenda for the meeting includes a recap of our March meeting workshop results, a GIS Day planning workshop, and several members of the CenTexGIS community will share and rehearse their presentations for the ESRI UC next month in San Diego, CA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please try to arrive a few minutes early to find parking, check any bags at entry, and sign in.  The Austin History Center shares a parking lot with the Austin Public Library, and street side metered parking as well as a pay garage across the street are available parking options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the meeting we will head over to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theaustinalehouse.com/&quot;&gt;Austin Ale House&lt;/a&gt; for happy hour!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, one lucky winner will go home with a great DOOR PRIZE.  We hope to see you in a couple weeks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 13:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/events/gis/centex-gis-meeting-june</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/events/gis/centex-gis-meeting-june</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>Events</category>
        
        <category>GIS</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
